Guide to the Jesse H. Jones Family and Personal Papers, 1841-2000 MS 252
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series II: Personal (JHJ), 208250 (Box 16-92)
  - Subseries T: Realia/memorabilia (oversize), 210620 (Box 79-94)
    - Audio/Visual, 210708 (Box 91-92)
      - Aluminum and acetate records, 210734 (Box 92)
        - "Reception to Howard Hughes", 7/15/1938; lp_18; 210741 (Box 92)
          This digitized audio file consists of one master copy wav, one access copy mp3, and jpegs of the record as well as transfer metadata.
        - "Business government" (sides 1,2,3,4), 10/7/1940; lp_19, lp_20; 210742 (Box 92)
        - "Investments and insurance" (sides 1,2,3,4), 11/2/1940; lp_21, lp_22; 210743 (Box 92)
        - "Loans to small businesses" (sides 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,16), 3/19/1939; lp_23, lp_24, lp_25, lp_26, lp_27, lp_28, lp_29, lp_30; 210744 (Box 92)
        - "Presentation of deed, Will Rogers Hospital" (sides 1,2,3,4), 2/25/1937; lp_31, lp_32; 210745 (Box 92)
    - Portfolio scrapbook: JHJ induction into Pantheon of Philanthropy Hall of Fame, 1979
    - Silver bowl: "To the Honorable Jesse Holman Jones from the Trustees of the Committee for Economic Development in token of their admiration and regard and as a tribute to his vision and leadership in the founding of CED in 1942, presented May 20, 1948" (Box 93)
    - Silver desk set: "Replica of pen and ink stand used in signing the Declaration of Independence; presented to National Bank of Commerce by Insurance Company of North America 1954" (Box 93)
    - Wooden gavel: "DemoCon Houston, June 1926" [for 1928 Democratic National Convention] (Box 93)
    - Wooden gavel: "Houston 1928" [engraving on silver star] (Box 93)
    - Wooden gavel: "Made and presented by Sam Houston State Teachers College, Huntsville to National Democratic Convention, Houston, TX 1928" [engraved on silver plate] (Box 93)
    - [brass] "Key to Fort Worth/Jesse H. Jones" (Box 93)
    - Brass key/thermometer: "America's pioneer tunnel superhighway 180 miles-7 tunnels under Appalachian mtns. linking Harrisbury-Pittsburgh, PA" (Box 93)
    - Medallion: "The American Red Cross to commemorate the vision and achievement of the War Council 1917-1919" (Box 93)
    - Medallion: "TWA passenger inaugural flight aboard 4 engine Stratoline" (Box 93)
    - Ribbon: "National Committee Democratic National Convention, Jesse H. Jones", 1928 (Box 93)
    - Ribbon/medallion: "The National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution Good Citizenship Medal, Honorable Jesse H. Jones, Feb. 22, 1956" (Box 93)
    - Trowel: "Presented to Honorable Jesse H. Jones, Occasional Lodge, Washington, Dec. 16, 1941 by M.W. Ara M. Daniels, Grand Master FA-AM, D of C, 1941" (Box 93)
    - Jones family crest and info, deBeaufort library info (Box 93)
    - Medallion: "J. Russell Young School of Expression Graduate" (Box 93)
    - Medallion: "Member Order of Knight of San Jacinto-Jesse H. Jones" (Box 93)
    - Framed oval silver tray: "Presented to Jesse H. Jones in appreciation of his distinguished service to the State of Texas from the Dallas Chamber of Commerce, April 9, 1928" (Box 94)
    - Framed letter: Oct. 10, 1921, A.D. Simpson from Jesse H. Jones (Box 94)
    - Framed program: Association of Rice Alumni Homecoming 1956 (Mrs. J.H. Jones) (Box 94)
    - Bound calendars of the U.S. House of Representatives and history of legislation, final edition, 78th Congress, 1944 (Box 94)